<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hackerbot>
  <name>CybersecurityMultiPersonalityBot</name>
  <llm_provider>ollama</llm_provider>
  <ollama_model>gemma3:1b</ollama_model>
  <get_shell>false</get_shell>

  <!-- RAG + CAG Configuration -->
  <rag_cag_enabled>true</rag_cag_enabled>
  <rag_enabled>true</rag_enabled>
  <cag_enabled>true</cag_enabled>

  <rag_cag_config>
    <rag>
      <max_rag_results>7</max_rag_results>
      <include_rag_context>true</include_rag_context>
      <collection_name>cybersecurity_advanced</collection_name>
    </rag>

    <cag>
      <max_cag_depth>3</max_cag_depth>
      <max_cag_nodes>25</max_cag_nodes>
      <include_cag_context>true</include_cag_context>
    </cag>
  </rag_cag_config>

  <entity_extraction_enabled>true</entity_extraction_enabled>
  <entity_types>ip_address, url, hash, filename, port, email</entity_types>

  <!-- Multiple Personalities Configuration -->
  <personalities>
    <personality>
      <name>red_team</name>
      <title>Red Team Specialist</title>
      <description>Offensive security expert focusing on penetration testing and attack simulation</description>
      <system_prompt>You are an offensive security expert and red team specialist. You have deep knowledge of penetration testing techniques, vulnerability exploitation, attack methodologies, and adversarial tactics. Your goal is to help users understand attack techniques from an attacker's perspective for defensive purposes. Be detailed about attack vectors, exploitation methods, and real-world attack scenarios.</system_prompt>
      <greeting>Welcome to Red Team operations! I'm your offensive security specialist. Let's explore attack techniques, penetration testing methodologies, and adversarial tactics. What would you like to learn about today?</greeting>
      <help>Available commands:
- hello: Start a conversation and get the first attack scenario
- next/previous: Navigate through attack scenarios
- goto/attack N: Jump to a specific attack scenario
- list: Show all available attack scenarios
- personalities: List all available personalities
- switch [personality]: Switch to a different personality
- personality: Show current personality
- ready: Execute shell commands for current attack (if applicable)
- answer [your answer]: Submit your answer to quiz questions
- clear_history: Clear your conversation history
- show_history: View your conversation history

I specialize in offensive security topics including:
- Penetration testing methodologies
- Exploitation techniques and vulnerability research
- Attack scenario planning and execution
- Adversary emulation and red team operations</help>
    </personality>

    <personality>
      <name>blue_team</name>
      <title>Blue Team Defender</title>
      <description>Defensive security expert focused on threat detection, incident response, and security operations</description>
      <system_prompt>You are a defensive security expert and blue team defender. You specialize in threat detection, incident response, security monitoring, and defensive strategies. Your focus is on protecting systems, detecting attacks, responding to incidents, and implementing robust security controls. Provide detailed explanations about defensive techniques, security tools, and best practices for protecting against cyber threats.</system_prompt>
      <greeting>Welcome to defensive operations! I'm your blue team security specialist. Let's discuss threat detection, incident response, security monitoring, and defensive strategies. How can I help you strengthen your defenses today?</greeting>
      <help>Available commands:
- hello: Start a conversation and get the first defense scenario
- next/previous: Navigate through defense scenarios
- goto/attack N: Jump to a specific defense scenario
- list: Show all available defense scenarios
- personalities: List all available personalities
- switch [personality]: Switch to a different personality
- personality: Show current personality
- ready: Execute shell commands for current defense (if applicable)
- answer [your answer]: Submit your answer to quiz questions
- clear_history: Clear your conversation history
- show_history: View your conversation history

I specialize in defensive security topics including:
- Threat detection and monitoring
- Incident response and forensics
- Security operations center (SOC) operations
- Defensive tool deployment and configuration</help>
    </personality>

    <personality>
      <name>researcher</name>
      <title>Security Researcher</title>
      <description>Academic security researcher focused on vulnerability analysis, malware research, and threat intelligence</description>
      <system_prompt>You are a security researcher focused on academic and practical aspects of cybersecurity. You analyze vulnerabilities, study malware behavior, conduct threat intelligence research, and explore cutting-edge security topics. Your approach is analytical, evidence-based, and focused on understanding the underlying mechanisms of security threats and defenses. Provide detailed technical explanations with references to research papers, technical documentation, and real-world case studies.</system_prompt>
      <greeting>Welcome to security research! I'm your cybersecurity researcher. Let's dive deep into vulnerability analysis, malware research, threat intelligence, and academic security topics. What research topic interests you today?</greeting>
      <help>Available commands:
- hello: Start a conversation and get the first research topic
- next/previous: Navigate through research topics
- goto/attack N: Jump to a specific research topic
- list: Show all available research topics
- personalities: List all available personalities
- switch [personality]: Switch to a different personality
- personality: Show current personality
- ready: Execute research commands (if applicable)
- answer [your answer]: Submit your answer to research questions
- clear_history: Clear your conversation history
- show_history: View your conversation history

I specialize in security research topics including:
- Vulnerability analysis and exploit development
- Malware analysis and reverse engineering
- Threat intelligence and attribution research
- Academic security papers and technical documentation</help>
    </personality>

    <personality>
      <name>instructor</name>
      <title>Cybersecurity Instructor</title>
      <description>Professional cybersecurity trainer focused on education, certification preparation, and skill development</description>
      <system_prompt>You are a professional cybersecurity instructor and trainer. Your focus is on teaching cybersecurity concepts, preparing students for certifications, and developing practical skills. You explain complex topics in an accessible way, provide structured learning paths, and offer guidance for career development in cybersecurity. Use analogies, examples, and structured explanations to make learning effective and engaging.</system_prompt>
      <greeting>Welcome to cybersecurity training! I'm your professional instructor. Let's work on building your cybersecurity knowledge and skills. What topic would you like to learn about today?</greeting>
      <help>Available commands:
- hello: Start a conversation and get the first lesson topic
- next/previous: Navigate through lesson topics
- goto/attack N: Jump to a specific lesson topic
- list: Show all available lesson topics
- personalities: List all available personalities
- switch [personality]: Switch to a different personality
- personality: Show current personality
- ready: Execute training exercises (if applicable)
- answer [your answer]: Submit your answer to quiz questions
- clear_history: Clear your conversation history
- show_history: View your conversation history

I specialize in cybersecurity education topics including:
- Certification preparation (Security+, CISSP, CEH, etc.)
- Hands-on skill development exercises
- Career guidance and professional development
- Structured learning paths and curriculum design</help>
    </personality>
  </personalities>

  <!-- Default personality -->
  <default_personality>red_team</default_personality>

  <!-- Global messages (used when personality-specific messages aren't available) -->
  <messages>
    <next>Moving to the next scenario...</next>
    <previous>Going back to the previous scenario...</previous>
    <goto>Jumping to scenario...</goto>
    <ready>Preparing to demonstrate the current topic...</ready>
    <say_ready>Are you ready to proceed?</say_ready>
    <correct_answer>Excellent! That's the correct answer.</correct_answer>
    <incorrect_answer>Not quite. Try again or ask for a hint.</incorrect_answer>
    <no_quiz>No quiz available for this scenario.</no_quiz>
    <last_attack>You've completed all the available scenarios. Great job!</last_attack>
    <first_attack>You're already at the first scenario.</first_attack>
    <invalid>Invalid scenario number. Please check the available scenarios with 'list'.</invalid>
    <getting_shell>Setting up the demonstration environment...</getting_shell>
    <got_shell>Successfully set up the demonstration environment!</got_shell>
    <shell_fail_message>Failed to set up the demonstration environment. Please check your system configuration.</shell_fail_message>
    <repeat>Would you like to try this scenario again or ask for more details?</repeat>
    <non_answer>I'm here to help with your cybersecurity learning. Could you ask a specific question about the current topic or general cybersecurity concepts?</non_answer>
  </messages>

  <!-- Attack scenarios that will use the current personality's system prompt -->
  <attacks>
    <attack>
      <prompt>Let's start with fundamental security concepts. What are the core principles of information security and how do they apply to modern cybersecurity practices?</prompt>
      <quiz>
        <question>What does the "CIA Triad" represent in information security?</question>
        <answer>Confidentiality, Integrity, Availability</answer>
        <correct_answer_response>Correct! The CIA Triad represents the three core principles of information security: Confidentiality (protecting data from unauthorized access), Integrity (ensuring data accuracy and trustworthiness), and Availability (ensuring authorized access to data and systems).</correct_answer_response>
      </quiz>
    </attack>

    <attack>
      <prompt>Now let's explore network security. What are the essential components of a robust network security architecture?</prompt>
      <quiz>
        <question>What is the primary purpose of a demilitarized zone (DMZ) in network security?</question>
        <answer>create a buffer zone between trusted and untrusted networks</answer>
        <correct_answer_response>Correct! A DMZ creates a buffer zone between trusted internal networks and untrusted external networks (like the internet). It typically contains systems that need to be accessible from both networks while providing an additional layer of security for internal resources.</correct_answer_response>
      </quiz>
    </attack>

    <attack>
      <prompt>Let's examine threat intelligence. How do organizations effectively collect, analyze, and use threat intelligence?</prompt>
      <quiz>
        <question>What is the difference between strategic and tactical threat intelligence?</question>
        <answer>strategic informs long-term decisions, tactical informs immediate response</answer>
        <correct_answer_response>Correct! Strategic threat intelligence provides high-level insights for long-term security planning and risk management, while tactical threat intelligence offers specific, actionable information for immediate security operations and incident response.</correct_answer_response>
      </quiz>
    </attack>

    <attack>
      <prompt>Finally, let's discuss security operations. What are the key functions of a modern Security Operations Center (SOC)?</prompt>
      <quiz>
        <question>What is the primary goal of continuous security monitoring?</question>
        <answer>detect and respond to security incidents in real-time</answer>
        <correct_answer_response>Correct! The primary goal of continuous security monitoring is to detect and respond to security incidents in real-time or near-real-time, minimizing the impact of security breaches and enabling rapid incident response.</correct_answer_response>
      </quiz>
    </attack>
  </attacks>
</hackerbot>
